there we go Linda show you beautiful
face
and welcome everybody to implementing
Vision
2024 because implementing is where it's
at we can have all the beautiful Visions
in the world if we don't Implement them
they're just nice sweet hot air dreams
right that's what this is all about so
we want to see what we can do to
implement and the Little Steps we can
take so that implementing becomes easy
and natural and also we want to see
where life happens and implements Us in
ways that we didn't expect and and how
to reinterpret what happens to us as a
step in the right
direction so that we always feel like
we're in control and in charge because
even when life throws
us bones or sticks right to stumble we
turn those sticks into tools to enhance
what we want to do so you know that's
always my people accuse me of positive
thinking how dare you it's like such a
crime all right
so
um The Mastermind Implement Vision
2024 is all
about becoming more Authentic Living and
implementing what you really feel you
want to do and I'm going to go straight
into practicality if you all have a
notepad and a pen or want to put it in
the chat down here I'm going to put the
things in the chat that we want to
quickly note down so and of course those
of you who want to and I know this is
going to be
up um
on YouTube later so that if you're not
here live you can still go through the
same steps and you need to know that in
my evolve
system I help you through all these
steps and the group helps you through
all these steps and Linda can tell us a
little bit more about that later because
she went through the program all right
so now take out your notepads and write
down
one your three most important goals or
achievements or change changes right
just pick three that are that really
seem important to you so if I close my
eyes of course everything is always so
important in our life right I will say
my
book my
University my
fitness right even though there's a lot
more on my plan
so stay with us and write down those
notes or in your mind for Monique who's
not able to to write right now um in
your mind repeat to yourself I want this
and that and the third as the most
important
things
and I don't want you to like argue with
yourself for for a long time just um
Andre is back in yeah just close your
eyes and allow what comes into your mind
first to be written
down when you make plans the beauty
about plans is as long as you have a
plan you can always revise it you can
always adapt it you can always alter
reinterpret the steps Etc but having a
plan is what makes it so much easier to
walk through
life because you're giving yourself
structure all
right and I'm going to put this in the
chat so
one three
goals can't type either
here
goals
[Music]
to
um three first steps
the mild
stones to
celebrate and oops
for
um
other
improvements
so that's another that's a list of just
other things you want to change for
example I want to allow myself to stand
more in my authority right I I tend to
acques and to like yeah
okay maybe you know you're right there
which is fine but standing in our
Authority is also very important
standing
in I am right for what I see I am
authentic I am right for what I
see okay so this these are the four
points to note down can you see in the
chat
yes
awesome um why don't I see them the
chat oh because I put my
participants list on over
it where do I put this thing um Johanna
yeah yes Andrea this
Al email wait who's talking Linda is
talking
H say that again please it wasn't
me was it Andrea Andrea you're Frozen
again
oh Andrea your connection isn't working
very well sorry about that just keep
trying I have this thing with my
colleague and friend Nell who lives up
in the mountains and whenever we have a
telephone conversation we have to like
dial back to each other at least five
times during a conversation because the
call always drops so that's just part
for the course shirely is
back okay shley says her microphone is
not working right now so that's why she
hasn't said hello
Regina is
back and here we
have who just came
back Linda shley Andrea Monique Regina
okay everybody is back
all right do you have your three
goals let's put yes in the
chat
so
book um
University
fitness is for me now the
three I assume that you all have put
down your three three goals
right yes yes I only have two
yeses um not everybody
can put their yeses in there I'm just
trying
to put my particip Pati somewhere okay
next First Steps three steps in the
right direction for sorry about the sun
coming in here but that's just what we
are dealing with when it's a sunny
cloudy weather
change
um all right the three steps you can
take
toward one of the goals or all three of
the goal
so for me the three steps
include a weekly
routine so that would be
[Music]
routine especially for Fitness to really
stick to my routine which is very hard
for me because I am so averse to any
regimentation right it always feels like
prison to me when I have to do something
at the same time every time da da da da
it's a military approach but it helps us
enormously give yourself a little slack
but then make up for it on another day
or at another time or do an evening
workout when you scheduled it for the
morning Etc so routine is one step in
getting all three things accomplished
for me for you it maybe something else
for you it may be doing affirmations
every day or for you it maybe um writing
letters to your Congress person or you
know whatever it is that you
feel
is creating accountability for
yourself
um who did we lose we
lost we
lost Andrea
again okay but she's back
in um
all right what could be a second step
for
um step toward achieving your
goals for me it definitely is writing
letters
to um to podcasters that I would like to
interview with I mean either they
interview me or I interview them so
that's for me a big step
toward all three goals because of
course when launching a book that will
become even easier but even before then
I have to make those connections so and
step number
three for all three main
goals is in my case pursue the land I
just found another large piece of land
that would be great for our project and
the seller is willing to collaborate I'm
going back there with I've discussed it
with my architect and so forth so that
is definitely pursue the land is my step
three even though it seems a little
irrational because that's not going to
bring immediate income but it's going to
manifest something on the soil that I
feel needs to be manifested the internet
can always get crashed you know with one
little interference from another country
that we're trying to mess with right and
our entire internet goes kaban but a
piece of land is much harder to go kab
um when we um when we pursue
implementing
something so what are your three
steps okay monik is saying no I don't
know if there are achieve
achievable
well whether they're achievable or not
you will only find out once you take
steps toward them
no
so take the steps all
entrepreneurial existence all inventors
all creators have to take steps toward a
goal to find out
whether those goals are achievable and
many of us have long years of
experiencing that we seem to fail but in
the failure we've learned something
something so the next time we step into
the ring or we step forward um we are
better equipped to get
further well of course it always doesn't
depend just on one other person it
depends on so many circumstances coming
into falling into place right
and if it's your goal and not the other
person's goal
then the question is what's more
important maybe you have to shift your
goal to something that the other person
also
wants and then that becomes your goal if
the other person is not as important as
your goal you have to say okay this one
I'll do on my own thank you but you
can't be in on it so those are decisions
of course that you have to make but it
doesn't mean that there shouldn't be the
goal the goal being like I just said
either adapting to the
person
or the person having to adapt to you and
if they can't so be it you find another
way I just a few minutes ago before I
started the
Mastermind was saying to my son's
girlfriend kind of almost like my
daughter-in-law
um you know every problem always has at
least 25 Solutions you just have to open
your mind to finding ways around through
other me means of overcoming Etc so
there's never a definite no to a problem
you want to
solve sometimes it can only be solved in
your imagination and not on this planet
of course those are things when we try
to override physics and gravity we may
not succeed you know what I mean that
too of course happens where we just have
Illusions about what's possible on the
Planet
but everything that is within the realm
of biology and physics
and
intention um can be
done
um so think about whether that's someone
else whether you need to adapt to that
someone else because that someone else
is
important so adapt your goal to them or
allow yourself to pursue the project
with or without
them all right
um then very very important number three
on my list here is celebrating
Milestones celebrating mil stones and
sorry I'm going
to close this little cloth curtain
thingy
a little bit more okay that's better so
you can see my face as opposed to that
bleached out thing
blotch okay
um what I'm saying is that we need to
celebrate every step that we have
achieved so even though I haven't even
secured the funds for the purchase of
the land that I've just discovered I'm
celebrating the fact that there is
another piece of land because we already
lost
one um where the seller is willing to
work with us and where the land has
incredible
possibilities and a beautiful view over
the entire Hudson Valley it's just
breathtaking and that kind of thing so
even if this one also fails I'm
celebrating the the fact that it exists
and that there is the
possibility and that means that even if
this one again doesn't work out like the
previous one there will be another
possibility so and that is true for all
of life there will always be multiple
possibilities if we allow ourselves to
see them if we don't get fixated on my
this way or the highway kind of thing
right there's always
way so therefore celebrating Milestones
becomes very important celebrate every
little step I'm celebrating myself that
I'm sitting down every day now and write
at least one little paragraph for the
book The the core of the book already
exists but it has to be expanded upon
its my educational
thesis and therefore I must again
establish a routine and of course I
tried to make that routine every morning
at 10 o'clock I spend an hour writing
the book doesn't work in my life for so
many reasons because I also have family
living in my house who have all kinds of
agendas and emergencies right to deal
with but I make sure that whatever time
of the day I write something on my book
how is your experience writing your book
Andrea now you're actually really clear
and
beautiful um it's it's
challenging it's challenging for the
schedule and so what I'm thinking about
now
is doing having like some amount or some
pages every day and then setting aside
one day or maybe even two days where I
have a big chunk of time
like maybe not the whole day but you
know four hours one morning when I don't
have to be anywhere or in the afternoon
or something so that I can uh double
down
and get stuff done so I'm going to try
this two-pronged daily and then maybe
two bigger chunks during the week but I
haven't got my schedule
I'm doing that now right that we're here
now is the scheduling time a beautiful
now I I know from Andrea that she also
has the challenge of a 96 year old
mother right who has all 95 she just we
talked about 95 for so
long yes all right 95 year old mother
and you never know what responsibilities
come at any time
so again it's important that you allow
yourself the flexibility even if you
have to go down there and be with your
mother and that's a two-hour travel what
do you do in the two-hour travel you put
your your phone on a holder in your car
and put it on record in whatever program
you want to use you can even use
Messenger on Facebook or something and
record that chapter verbally and have it
transcribed because all devices do that
now so that's a way of getting your
pages done by not having the excuse well
I couldn't sit down and write because I
had to be in my car for example right
it's just another of finding that
way through water adapts to the
circumstances that are in its way right
and still down
right
to the
ocean all right
um Linda do you want to chime in with
what your goals and Milestones are
Regina do you want to chime in anybody
can just chime
in all right you want me to um I'll tell
you what my three goals are that a good
start Okay so I want to uh so you know
I've been keto right for over a year so
I'm looking to just overall qualify your
keto for everybody because people have a
different
idea oh okay so I um I'm looking to
improve my high raw vegan keto diet
right
so you I've been doing it for over a
year but you know I see that I feel like
there's always room for improvement M so
now that I know that I I've been able to
maintain it I want to focus on uh
expanding my menu you know I I have a
lot of quick go-to Foods because I like
things that are fairly
affordable um I want I've been just
really struggling with coming up with
a palatable green smoothie that has all
the superfoods I want that's low carb
but
that's not repulsive to drink it's like
I need something tasty and I just
haven't set aside the time to do that
like people make smoothies all the time
and you throw fruit you know you can
make them so delicious but when you
focus on a low carb smoothie and then
you're adding spirulina or Moringa you
know all the you know all the right
greens it's uh it it it's its yumminess
so that's a goal which sounds silly
probably to the group but for me I feel
like I'm missing out on
these these important nutrients that I'm
probably not getting from my regular
diet because I just can't consume that
that many greens so so and that's
actually something that's been on my up
you know air quotes plate for quite a
while so that's a big goal for me this
this year you know sounds silly okay how
about want to
yeah I just want to say how about
sharing with a group that you will
gather around you who have similar
goals yeah that's a tough group to
find ah you would be surprised people
people switching you know people think
keto can only be done with meat and
dairy right right and you're doing it
without meat and without dairy and it
works obviously you're alive you look
great at your age and you know you're
fit and you're slender and all of that
good stuff um now I'm going to throw a
little wrench in your putting though and
that is that the
brain for you so that you can work out
what it is that you need requires sugars
and fats and if you can't give it enough
sugars you might want to work with the
fats you know and find the sweetness via
other things like Stevia or oh yes
exactly I do I do use deevia M fruit
right right yeah so we can talk more
about that but I'm just throwing it in
there your brain needs those things in
order to be able to work out what your
questions are kind of thing it's ironic
you know to put it that way but it's
true cool but you got your and no I I
really do think you need to join a bunch
of meat keto groups and demonstrate to
them that you can do
it in a different way literally I mean
that well I did just take a h a 4- day
class while it was kind of a um it was
called a fasting while feasting class by
Dr Rita and and it it's based on keto
and and surprisingly she's actually uh
plant-based in and hyra herself and has
been doing that for many years she she
has a functional medicine type of a
like in beautiful now carry knowledge
that's what I mean you know if if 2024
is not just about improving your own but
also carrying your mission into the
world that's why I'm saying you know
join those crazy keto groups and just
you know comment well great great that
sounds really great I can do the same
thing with greens and other other plant
stuff right that's what I think is is
exciting that you can bring that out
there and and rub a lot of people the
wrong way but they have to acknowledge
that it
works you're right Regina do you want to
chime
in you have to unmute
yourself hi can you hear me hi hi
okay one of my first goals is to
increase my Mobility especially since I
fell and dislocated my shoulder so I
want to start with some stretching
exercises and then move up to some other
exercises as and work with my PT my
physical therapist yes you may also want
to look at Fitness over 50 that's my
fitness program and it allows a very it
approaches Fitness in a very gentle way
to increase muscle strength and not so
much on big stretches although I do big
stretches as you can see at the in in
the email that I just put out I don't
know whether you saw it you know with my
leg up in the air there 70 and with my
leg up in the air
so my my program is very gentle and it
achieves power through
repetition so just check it out I mean
there's lots on on YouTube Fitness over
50 on my YouTube channel johanna's ra
Foods sounds great okay so just just so
you know and and of course you know you
can always set up a time to talk to me
um if you wanted more of that but um you
sound younger than someone I'm
75 you sound great and I'm I was working
up until November when I felt I'm a
nurse and I and I plan to retire on um
May 1 if I but I'm out on workman's comp
right now so I'll just have to adjust
that however this works out awesome and
again you know I have a whole problem
where I a whole program not a problem a
whole program where I help people become
coaches Linda has gone through it that's
why I said you know she can tell us more
about that later um where I help you
evolve
into something that works for you as a
lifestyle and it includes
Fitness okay my next goal is to have
somebody come in and help me
declutter yes I actually I actually have
someone coming at 3 o'clock this
afternoon to interview I don't know if
she'll be a good fit or not but I'm
least I'm making a step in the right
direction
congratulations
decluttering and again you know I have a
mastermind on clean and declutter it's
also on my YouTube it's so important and
unfortunately we have to do it again and
again it's not something that is done
once and then stays Because unless we
are very ocdc you know where we just
have to have things in order all the
time um it just reutter I was just
walking through my house this morning
and saying oh man we're up for it yeah
and my next goal is to I have several
little house repairs I need done so I'm
interviewed a handyman yesterday now I
don't I gave him a project I don't he's
supposed to get back with me on Monday
but if he doesn't work out I will keep
looking at because I don't need all
these little things building
up and and not getting repaired that
needs to be repaired I'm a very private
person so having somebody come in my
home is like an invasion to me I hear
you sounds
funny oh it's it's very real um a little
safer way to go and look for I don't
know whether you looked on like there's
an Angie's List I think called
I yeah where people have reviews and so
forth yeah and then of course I ask
people whether they are going to be my
assistants or whether they're going to
be cleaning personnel always for their
own lifestyle and their understanding of
because I also want everything non-toxic
you know I don't want any right bad
chemicals yeah right so make sure that
you also ask people for whether they
understand a non-toxic take a
non-chemical approach so this is a brave
new front letting people come into my
house I mean I'm an extrovert at my job
and all it's just my home life is just
very private
yeah I hear you and that's the truth for
so
many um I was just helping a client of
mine young teenager um write about Ella
Fitzgerald you know and we learn from
her biography how incredibly shy she was
and how self-doubting she was but then
she gets on stage and suddenly something
releases in her and she feels like
nothing can happen to her and the
audience carries her just emotionally
mentally or you know spiritually maybe
and she's fine and then she gets off the
stage and she's back to this inter
terribly shy person right so much so
that people like Marilyn Monroe help her
to get get through to people who will
then um invite her to clubs even though
it's a time of segregation still and you
know Jim Crow is still kind of in place
so I'm just telling you you are not
alone and often great people are very
shy so
okay well thank
you go for it Regina so good I hope to
talk to you
more all right Monique have do you have
can you talk about your main goals oh no
you just talked about
your um go ahead did I
forget Monique can you unmute
yourself I don't know she may not not be
present and we we lost Charlie again um
good so I already told you what my goals
are let's move
on
um what are all the little things list
of improvements just jut down things
like our own character Improvement for
example I want to be
um both standing in my like I said my
own authority but I also want to spend a
lot of time to understand the context
from which people come with their
opinions and belief systems
and um often very irrational and
illogical to me um opinions on things
right but when we understand Humanity in
a larger context anyway that's one of my
things so I want to be more
understanding yet standing in my
authority and finding ways to explain
things um in a way that is not
condescending and in a way that is not
[Music]
um yeah bashing unders for not
understanding kind of you know what I'm
saying not getting mad about the world
for doing all this crazy stuff that goes
on but coming from an understanding oh
because we have this system that is why
they act this way because we have this
belief system that the more money the
better the more control the more money
and you know all of these are systems
that we're stuck in and when we keep
reminding ourselves that they're stuck
in this system the important part is to
work on the next system as opposed to um
complaining about the fact that it is
like a it
is so that's one of my things and then
there's little things like also the
cleaning and decluttering the regular
cleaning the
[Music]
um the making things pretty the creating
peace and Beauty the're playing more
piano I have this big piano sitting
there it hasn't been tuned so I don't
feel like playing it and you know all of
these things the little things so I want
you to make a list of little things that
you want to improve this year or get
back to that you did earlier or so all
the little
things and I'm going to take a second
too to write mine down even though I was
just talking like crazy so that you can
all have some quiet time thinking about
what all your improvements
are
Andrea keeps dropping out and coming
back it's almost like
regular
all right I'm sure you've come to quite
a few things does anyone want to start
sharing and by the way you don't have to
unmute your you don't have to mute
yourself all the time you can just leave
your unmute on unless you have loud
noises in the background perfectly fine
so that there's so few of us we can can
all talk to each
other well excuse me I'll start with
um um with the number one little
thing which is um similar to your number
one little thing Johanna and that is to
listen more and to slow down so
similarly to
um allow someone to finish talking even
when although I really find that
difficult when I can see that their
initial premise is
like no you know you don't get what I'm
saying you're on the wrong path I don't
need an exposition let's clean this up
now but so I don't know how much I'm
going to be able
to chill on that but in the G General as
a general principle to
listen to people more yes you can go in
your mind to oh I see why you are
thinking that I see where you're coming
from I see why your life has set you up
to think like
that that's very condescending I it's
very condescending to say that no all I
see why you think that because you're
because you're a limited ncome
poop no you don't you don't need to add
that you're a limited income poop we all
perceive and process according to our
training according to our imprint
according to our training and then comes
in the higher
intelligence that we either connect with
or not so much and that again often is
due to everybody's life experience you
know um just this morning I commented on
a um famous physicist's um on physicist
postings on on Tik Tok
um we can
only perceive the reality according to
what how we see hear the phenomena
observed and how we inter interpret them
and how we then interpret them into our
existing system into using the words we
have using the concepts we have and all
of those you could also see as
projections into the world right and if
you acknowledge that even my
understanding of the world is a
projection then of course everybody
else's interpretation of the world is a
projection and we can to a certain
extent understand why they have a
certain understanding why did people
have the understanding that the sun
circles around the flat earth right
because that's what they could see and
hear and they had no reason not to think
that was the
reality that's just a simple example so
that's where I'm coming from when I'm
saying
allow to allow yourself to understand n
po yes
allow yourself to understand that people
have a limited ability to see and what
always baffles me is people have a
limited ability for
logic meaning that if I hold this pen if
I let go it will drop right that's logic
because I know there is such a thing as
gravity so when people have a limited
understanding of
logic a a lot of
things
go hi high no Haywire not Highwire
Haywire in their own minds and then you
have to find things that put things in
order like religion like a political
system like something a belief system
that you can hold on
to so that's where I'm coming from when
I'm saying understand the context and
while yes that may sound condescending
to somebody who uh is listening to
me I still have to say well that's what
I can see in my
interpretation and if I if that's what I
can see in my interpretation you know
you see me in your
interpretation but is there any Common
Ground do we have any logic do we have
the logic that there's gravity right
maybe we start there what other
commonality do we have where we see
things as a reality that works the same
way you know I have these arguments with
people about
capitalism
exploitation super gain Etc feudalism
and colonialism and all these various
forms of the same system these are
systems and the people caught in that
system believe that they're doing the
right thing
whether they're chopping other people to
pieces or whether they're
um building roads for other
people you know it's
it's always a projection
of what our belief system allows
for so sorry for that long rent can
somebody please Chim in chime in to the
nink
poops
I love that of course hey this is Regina
yes um I think being more
patient is something that I need to work
on I'm a a um night supervisor at the
hospital which I work at and I have to
think on my feet a lot because the buck
stops with me you know if we have a
maintenance
emergency if oh we have some you know
there's just all kinds of things that
you handle in that position and I seem
to do that well but being
patient with
myself um also I would like to improve
my computer
skills um there's a lot more I could
learn um and um you know exploring
meditation more
wonderful there you have it and those
are all qualities that will enhance the
big goals
substantially all
right by the way I love your glasses and
the color of your sweater oh thank
you I would wear these more but these
are real glass and they always fall off
when I make a certain movement or put
them on my head so yeah they're they're
they're cute they're from
Europe thank you
um well that's also about you know
having that thing for ourselves that we
like
to
be in
a in a shell that represents us right
and my shell can be all kinds of things
like I said you know sweatpant at the
bottom and and Blazer at the top
um great
um Linda do you want to share your
little
improvements yes sure so yeah things I'd
like to improve and in 2024 I'd like to
set up a routine to
read every day more consistently you
know I I buy books and they sit on the
shelf and I just you know do audiobooks
I I just don't make time and I think
that that's uh I don't think my time
could be better spent than to start
reading more I'd like to start uh
journaling every day I I get
uh I start journaling I I sto doing it I
get back in I'm very intermittent with
it and I'd like to make that you I guess
this year I'd like to focus on
consistent routines so I'd like to
journal more I'd like to read more um
I'd like to maybe be a little more
social I'm I'm also as you know I'm
pretty introverted and I I don't I don't
actually venture out a lot so I think
just trying to make the effort to be a
little bit more engaging or engaged with
other people my neighbors just you know
be a little bit more uh you I get
invited out to dinner maybe I go you
stuff like that so um I think that would
be good then uh for my well for my diet
I would like I have a habit of eating
too close to my bedtime so I H which I
don't believe is good for me and you
know I know a lot about nutrition is
intent
so I would like to focus on you know
finishing my meal wrapping up you know
four o'clock five at the latest and then
yeah because I'm usually in bed by 8 you
know I'm up at like 3:30 4 o'clock so I
would much
rather which is fine because I I mean I
do have a good exercise routine I've got
I've got you know I don't mind I the
morning time is just is just the best
for me I enjoy it so that's what I'd
like to do I have several colleagues who
do that including my business coach you
know who goes to sleep at 8:30 with her
son um and gets up at 3:00 in the
morning and does her alone time yeah and
and but others also in the business
World also successful like um what's her
name pretty crazy cancer um oh Chris
Chris yeah you know she says I'm not a
morning person My Life Starts at 10 or
11 right in the morning and and then it
goes late at night but you know it does
not impact your the success rate Picasso
was a night person right and so many
artists have all these different agendas
so I'm just saying there's no one way of
structuring your day correctly it really
that's I'm also want to put that out
there for everybody even when I teach
the Evolve system it's very important
that everybody adapts it to
their personal biological biochemical
and
societal needs right we all have
different you know I I used to argue
while I have teenagers and young adults
in my house and they have a late night
style lifestyle and I want to join them
in discussions at 11 o'clock at night or
at midnight right and that's I love that
so um that's not always going to be my
excuse I just have to come to terms with
the fact that I'm not a five
o'clock AM
person and it's okay I have to be okay
with it I don't have to have the
ambition of Shifting that and vice versa
and there others I was just
remembering when I lived in Berlin with
my um writer director film director um
partner
and he would write until 2 in the
morning because that that was his thing
to write right but I would go to sleep
at 10 11 and and be out doing my music
stuff or my my one woman shows or
whatever I was doing rehearsing um we
can make that work even with a partner
you know when he crawled into bed in the
middle of the night and we would cuddle
for a few minutes with me completely
asleep but I loved that so you know you
can make that work
too it doesn't have to be that both are
on the same schedule
even yeah just just so you know there's
no judgment on when you have have your
schedule that goes for you too Andrea
you know find the time that works for
you it doesn't have to be every morning
at 9 o'clock sharp for some people that
works to have an exact
time because otherwise they will always
be self-judging you know oh my God I
didn't get this done again
all that's not
helpful do it whenever you
can but do
it all right Charlie do you want to
chime in in the
chat what your improvements are this
year I I see that your microphone you
say your microphone is not
working
but um well we'll we'll see it if you if
you do chime
in so um
Monique do you want to comment on the
someone else
and what when you really ask your heart
self what that
means to your
life I mean sometimes there's also
Financial dependence or you have kids
together and you know all of those kind
of things if you want to comment on that
and or find a couple of things that you
can improve no matter which way the
pendulum
goes
yeah nobody's judging here we're all
we're all in
love go for
it
we hear you breathing but we don't hear
your
words and if you say you're not ready
that's fine too or put it in the
chat okay don't want to talk as fine
to
um allow yourself to embrace whatever
goes on emotionally right now with you
and give yourself a big hug from all of
us um again it's
you that
matters all right moving on I know it's
our time is getting longer here so
moving on on to three more things that
we need to become aware of number
one your big why for your goal this year
your big
why is often hard to Define but try to
find one definition of your big
why um number two is which are the
people that will be in support of you
and that can help help
you um it's not necessarily the same
sometimes you know that we have personal
friends who will support us emotionally
or share food or you know talk things
through talk things through while going
on a walk you know I love love doing
that with friends um but also people
maybe in like last year or the year
before I got a lot of Grant and things
like that also people in other power
positions who can help um or benefit you
for your projects or your goals or um or
hire you or you know there's many things
that can be helpful in your progress and
that's what I want you to focus on as a
as a second position here so number one
your big why number
two people and avenues that will have
help people that will help because it
it's always people that make the
decisions even if you apply for Grants
and stuff like
that or find find investors or so forth
and and number
three who can help you with
accountability and the follow
through um of course two and three kind
of go hand inand but it's important that
you have people to hold you accountable
now when you're in a group like like in
a
program where others are also pursuing
their goal that's where I wanted to have
Linda chime in
[Music]
um then you have others who are pursuing
their goals and they can be different
but they're holding you accountable
because you have to
present what you achiev during the the
week or month that just passed in when
you join such a program right so of
course my program being the super happy
body program and the evolved system but
there are many programs out there that
are
helpful and hold you accountable
unfortunately with friends it's really
difficult because there is no
structure you can work through with
friends that's why point2 right
um but they won't be the strict
structure that is holding you
accountable month after month after
month as much as I've tried that all my
life with friends it just never quite
works out but a coach will hold you
accountable others in your class or in
your meetup group that is really where
you're committing to something
they will hold you accountable and then
you'll hold yourself accountable so we
all need Community to do that for
ourselves
and um yeah for me I have a couple of
groups that I need to join not just on
paper or not just on the internet but
actually um physically go
to go to them like what Linda was saying
you know physically go to the groups
that I've signed up for and be there
and
join their agendas to a certain extent
okay so number one y buai number
two people who can help number
three
accountability
everybody
done okay not
yet take another
minute Monique when you say the other
person wants no contact with me and
that's my goal is your goal no contact
or is your goal establishing contact
even though they don't want contact I'm
not understanding
that just say A or B A being that you
want them to have no
contact B being that you're trying to
get in
contact that you're trying to get in
contact with somebody who doesn't want
contact oh yes
yeah
yeah I have people in my life and
surroundings who are trying to get in
contact with their own parents or with
their own
children
and it
doesn't
[Music]
happen and
while yeah uh I have a younger sister
some of you have heard me talk about
her who
is mentally outside of the range we call
normal um and for many years I tried to
connect and basically streamline her
into something that can function in the
world and then there was a point in
time where I said to myself and to her
mentally you chose this
life on your
[Music]
own with your way of doing
life who am I to impose what I consider
normal
you chose this life of course comes from
a point of view where we understand that
when we or when I the being comes into
this Incarnation into this physical body
into this
form um we already have made some
choices sometimes and very often those
choices change during the life
experience but sometimes they
don't and
H
yeah sometimes we've put an enormous
amount of effort in helping somebody who
cannot in this lifetime accept or have
that help and it can be the other way
around too we're trying to get somebody
to see that they can help us
and it is not happening so and everybody
has to find that point in time where
that is where we say okay
now I understand that that's your
way I don't know whether this is helpful
but I just wanted to put that out there
as my experience and I know that many
have connected with that
experience whether they were my clients
or family and
friends
yeah all right let's have a few ideas of
those who are ready with their big
why people who help and um
accountability who wants to start
okay you go Linda awesome
so my big why I
guess my you know my whole I feel like
there's an echo and I'm sorry about that
I don't know why it's not on this end
okay good so my big why I I I I guess I
would say my whole life has been focused
around nutrition since you know my my
20s when I went vegetarian then vegan
then you know focused on raw food and
you know I'm always evolving and it
seems like whatever I'm doing in my life
my primary focus is on nutrition and my
well-being and you know sharing that
knowledge if people are receptive or
open to it um so I I say that's still my
big why whatever ever I decide to
do you know this year you know I'm still
thinking about what my next chapter is
going to be you know when I retire um
just in a couple of years and just what
I you know what what I want my focus on
and I I think it's going to my big why
is always just suround you know it's
always just around nutrition so yeah
beautiful my people just support me now
I have to say my my husband's super
supportive he's always been supportive
he might think that my ideas are wacky
and out there I mean we have completely
opposite diets we have you know
our completely the opposite he W
congratulations to you for for for
balancing that yeah he's he's uh exactly
the opposite you know he's he's uh yeah
if he doesn't get meet every three hours
I I I think he' collaps he's just that's
just we're very different on that you
know but we were different when we met
and it just been you know we're
different in other ways but that's been
a pretty big one um and then I think but
he's always been like I say very
supportive and anything I've I've
pursued he rallies behind me he'll try
to find people that can help get me
where I want to be you know when I first
you know was uh thinking about doing
something around coaching you know many
years ago he was trying to set me up
with a chiropractor and get me in my own
office where I could do consultations
he's always like that and it's always me
that puts the breakes on says oh you
know I don't I'm not ready oh I you or
I'm too shy to really get started and
and jump into this type of a lifestyle
you know and you know and and then the
whole you know I G to make money doing
this and is this something
sustainable you know that's there's so
much surrounding that but he's you know
so I'd say he's probably my biggest Ally
as far as supporting me and for
accountability I I don't know I uh you
know I'd like to think I could be
self-accountable
but I I like like I say I I I have
routines that I have very very honorable
intentions that never quite manifest you
know like the whole smoothie thing I've
been thinking about for you know going
on two years and again I just don't get
around with so I don't know I'd have to
think about getting
into like you say finding a support
group or doing you know something where
there's some some level of well did you
get that done did you do that again and
and you know yeah wasn't that a little
better when you were in class with us
that's exactly you know my my segue into
that did make a huge difference in in my
progress
100% I mean the bottom line is we all
need that it's just a fact yeah I mean
there are very very few people who are
entirely
self-driven I mean even I just recently
did this whole um podcast about Cat
Williams and integrity and why it
matters you know but he is a genius kid
who literally sits in the library for
eight hours every day um and studies and
studies and studies because he reads
eight books a day you know one of those
photographic memory brains that just
page page page page oh I already know
what this chapter is about next page Etc
right and it works but you have to have
an IQ of 163 I think he says he has and
um you know Mena member and all of that
but we we most of us don't have that but
even that of course gives a framework if
the library people know you're there
eight hours every day you want to show
up and show off right that that's what
you can do so it is also kind of an
accountability system that you set for
yourself you know what I'm
saying so allow yourself those kind of
structures that help you show up for
yourself in the ways where your
weaknesses
are and of course I'm happy to talk more
about that with you all right who wants
to go next Andrea or Monique or
Regina Shirley you you can put in the
chat Monique are you
ready I'm seeing you you unmuted
yourself or are just staying unmuted
that's fine
too
Regina yeah I want peace that's very
important to me I um don't feel a lot of
Peace you don't feel a lot of Peace yeah
okay um you know I always ask my
spiritual guides to help me every day
because they're there um so I think if I
do some of these things I'll will gather
a better sense of Peace
yeah um my son even though he lives in
Seattle he is very good at saying to me
well have you done this did you do
that um my daughter she does but she's
an extremely different personality from
me but um she does you know try to coach
me and see if I'm doing what I voiced to
her um what was the third thing I can't
remember
well that's you you just spoke to
accountability the middle thing was
friends and avenues with people that
will help you implement what you want so
if you're saying you're looking for more
peace or looking for more structure in
your life it would be that you could
join a meditation group you could
um apply
for whatever a schoolish to travel to
India and join an ashram for a few
months or you know whatever I I'm just
pulling things out of the top of my head
um
but if you feel that something would
move you toward that inner
peace find those Avenues not just among
your friends but also out there that can
and it always involves of course people
because none of this is without human
beings right it doesn't exist without
human beings creating peace in your life
you could also say Okay I want to go
into the woods every other day and sit
under a particular tree and meditate
there that of course is also working
toward your peace and does not
necessarily involve other people however
it is
easier when we put it out there with
others who are also pursuing for example
meditation
um to then be able to report on that we
did
right once we put it out there once I
say you know I'm going to complete my
book this year I have put it out into
the world and I have much more of an
obligation to myself to complete
that plan and that's that's why it's
important to put it out to other human
beings who hold it in their memory that
we have said this and we want to live up
to that standard that we put out there
does that make sense
yes I I live in a very small southern
town um I have tried to find Unity
groups other things to get to where
those people are unless I start my own
group um I would have to travel 60 miles
or so yeah and again you know you may be
in a small town but in that small town
there may be a couple of people who are
curious about what breathing and
meditation are right maybe start with a
group that
does things that are so much in the
interwebs and in everybody's mind you
know whm Hof breathing and an ice bath
oh my
God I don't know I'm just putting it out
there that's really interesting windhoff
has come up a lot on the last week there
you
go yeah and and you may find that your
neighbor who never was into anything new
age
or spiritual right is curious about how
that thing works with cold water you
don't know or how that thing works with
making you salads or whichever other
approach it is that people can connect
to I have often spoken in libraries
where regular people and again this is
not condescending people who have never
tried raw food and all they can think of
is literally salad right that's all
that's on their mind come to these
lectures and are like wow I just learned
so much nobody has ever spoken to me
about the fact that biology on planet
Earth operates
all alive and Alive means every live
thing needs live
nutrients everything right and and of
course I go into all kinds of details
but they suddenly understand a new way
of looking at things even though I
brought them together by saying you know
make more salads or something like
that okay find your way and again I'm
happy to talk to you about that in more
detail you know what that can look like
connecting with the community in ways
that you may not have
previously um explored or thought
possible
because
seminar seminar
online yeah because we
also
um we
also often isolate ourselves so much
because like Andrea was saying you know
the nink poops get on our nerves with um
not understanding basic things whereas
we could go to
oh give me the answer how how
does how does
the um how does the deer eat the bark
does it put the bark on a grill first
or you know anyway I have I have my
crazy stories in my in my
lectures
um
whereby yeah whereby I make it funny and
fun to connect with other people that's
the same approach I would suggest
to Linda going into meet keto
groups
um yeah and again you know I'm happy to
talk to you about that more um Andrea
coming from
a
psychology
approach
um
allow people to
self-analyze and analyze each
other and listening to their
interpretation of what they see before
you show your
view I found that to be very very
helpful and I'm actually as I'm talking
reminding myself that that is what I do
when I lecture in places like libraries
where regular people people who have who
just want to learn how to make a salad
dressing by themselves you know are
suddenly interested in what it can do
for their body and for their health to
include more fresh food in their diets
[Music]
um all right
um wonderful conversations and I want to
wrap up
with the fact that of course we're still
all caught in a divisive system where we
have these little groups that hold tight
and you're not supposed if you're in
this group you're not supposed to go
into that group ever or find anything
that that group does correct or you know
because then you're immediately out oh
she's gone you know oh she's gone bad
because she's joined the opposition or
but
seeing humans as individuals caught in
systems
and
groupings allows you a much
Freer understanding and a much
Freer contextualizing I call that
putting things into the context of the
time we live in of the history stream
that we live in and seeing how that
stream is allowing you especially since
we're all women here right we are coming
into our own we are coming into our
individual
intellectual
ability to express and participate in
the
leading of humanity the leadership of
humanity it's an amazing time to be
alive and I want you all to have that as
a closing thought you're here here and
if you're listening to this later you're
listening to this because you're moving
into a time where you come into your
feminine leadership and as a man you're
allowed to bring forth more of your
feminine Powers not losing your
masculinity that's not what I'm saying
but we all have both and just as we
women discover some of our masculine
traits you're allowed to discover some
of your feminine traits and that's the
next era of
partnership all
right it has been lovely for you to be
here and to have you here please look up
um real humans great Souls is my podcast
I'm putting it in the in the I talk a
little bit more openly about
things like I said I'm trying trying to
be more authentic without
getting um kicked
off and just the by another thing is
also for you Andrea the fact that we can
say to ourselves and to others well I
think differently because I know so much
is okay because we do know so much right
and it's not the other person's fault
that they don't know so much much and of
course we also have to admit that the
more we know the more we know how little
we know so there's just always so much
more to
know yes you're
responding talk to
me I think it's 90 minutes I think it's
time for a wrap and thank
you yeah
I'm just putting this out there and of
course you find me on johannas foods.com
make contact with me all of you
listening to this later um you will be
able to connect and have a great
2024 everybody want to say
goodbye good luck
everybody
bye
okay signing
off